Guilherme Castello

Guilherme Castello - guilhermecastello@gmail.com - Version 1.0, Set 2019

Read this resume in PDF here.

Systems Analist / Developer

I'm a systems analist/developer who works with many technologies, like Java, Microsoft .Net and Android.+

I have a bachelor degree in Systems Information and I work with software development since 2007.

I'm currently working as a team leader, systems analist and developer at <u>PROCERGS</u>. My team is responsible for maintain and develop new features for a system of the state traffic department.

Personal details

Name: Guilherme Medina Castello

Social Media: in/♡/Ƴ

Location: Porto Alegre/RS, Brazil
Email: guilhermecastello@gmail.com

Phone: +55 51 998816365

Main interests

- Java
- Agile methodologies
- Testing (junit/Arquillian/BDD)
- Continuous Delivery
- SOA/ Microservices
- Docker and containers related technologies
- Documentation (Asciidoctor)
- Functional languages (Kotlin/Groovy)
- Cloud (AWS and OpenShift)

Professional Experience

Systems Analyst / Developer at PROCERGS

☐ June 2010 to Now (On going)

PROCERGS - Cia. de Processamento de Dados do Rio Grande do Sul

Position Team leader - Systems analist - Developer (Java, Android, .Net) - Agile

- Create and maintain in house JavaEE based solutions for speed up internal development
- Part of a Technical team which supports 200+ developers
- Prospecting new technologies (R&D)
- Evangelizing good practice and disciplines of agile methodologies such as testing and continuous delivery
- Migration of legacy technology to service based architecture
- Helps maintain infrastructure tools like {link-wso2}[WSO2^], {link-app-dynamics}[AppDynamics^], <u>Jenkins</u>, {link-sonar} [Sonar^] and <u>Artifactory</u>
- Develop and maintain an internal (devops) tool to help developers in *App Servers management* (deploy applications, view logs, start/stop apps, logging configuration, create system props, enable blue/green deployment etc...)
- Write documentation and blog about best practices
- Drive/help teams to build delivery pipelines on Jenkins
- Migration of legacy applications (JavaEE 5 or below) to new stack (Java EE 7/8)
- worked 3 years (2011-2014) in internal software factory using scrum

Used technologies

- JavaEE 6/7 stack (mainly EJB, JSF, JPA/Hibernate)
- Swagger (RESTAPI)
- JBoss EAP 6/7 (application server)
- Jasper Reports
- Artifactory
- Jenkins
- Android
- Microsoft .Net Framework
- OracleDB
- Redmine/TFS
- SVN/GIT

Microsoft Developer at TOTVS

Febuary 2010 to June 2010

TOTVS

Position Microsoft Developer

• Worked with C# and ASP.Net in a web system for hospitals.

Used technologies

- C#
- ASP.NET
- Microsoft .Net Framework 3.5

- Jira
- OracleDB

Microsoft Developer at Rede&Imagem

₩ January 2009 to Febuary 2010

Rede & Imagem Tecnologias LTDA

Position Microsoft Developer

- Worked with systems analisis and design.
- Worked on desktop and web aplications using C# and ASP.Net.
- Designed SQL Server databases with Enterprise Architect.

Used technologies

- C#
- ASP.Net
- SQL Server
- Crystal Reports

Developer (Trainee) at Banrisul

⊞ July 2007 to January 2009

👺 Banrisul - Banco do Estado do Rio Grande do Sul

Position Developer Trainee

- Worked on migrating one of the main bank's system. It was coded in C and we created a new system in java.
- Worked in other applications with VB, ASP, C# and ASP.Net.

Used technologies

- JavaSE
- OracleDB
- Microsoft technologies (VB, ASP, C# and ASP.Net)

Technical Skills

Languages and Specifications

Java SE 7/8, C#, PHP, TypeScript, JavaScript, JSON, CSS and HTML

Application Servers

JBoss EAP 6/7, Bea Weblogic and Apache Tomcat/Tomee

Frameworks and Libraries

Java EE (JSF, JPA, EJB, Servlet, JSP), Primefaces, Microsoft .Net Framework, Adroid SDK and Angular

OS

Windows

Databases

Oracle, MySQL and SQL Server

Tools

Eclipse, Maven, Redmine, Subversion, Git, Jenkins, Artifactory, Astah, ERWin, Adroid Studio, Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Visual Studio

ADLM

TFS

Languages Skills

• Portuguese : Native

• English: Advanced

Education

Bachelor's degree: Bachelor in Sistems Information

- University: Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul (PUCRS)
- # 2009-2013 Concluded

Technical license: Technical in Sistems Information

- University: Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul (<u>UFRGS</u>), Porto Alegre, Brazil
- **#** 2006-2009 **Concluded**

Extracurricular activities

- Android Fundamentals Sisnema # 2011 Concluded
- Android Advanced Target Trust ## 2013 Concluded
- Dinamic Web Development with Java Target Trust ## 2014 Concluded
- UX and UI for mobile Target Trust # 2016 Concluded
- Angular Alura 2019 Concluded

Version 1.0

Last updated 2019-09-18 16:40:52 -0300